# Maria Deslis

deslis@colorado.edu

github.com/eternalearth888

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a passionate and effective software developer with interests from coding to design and I'm actively learning and teaching new skills all the time. I have three years experience programming Full-Stack Development in an Agile/Scrum environment and a few semesters of teaching programming under my belt. I am currently attending graduate school to learn how to use my creativity, code, and design skills to create as many new solutions as possible. Everything from UI/UX design to Game Design to Product Design and more! I love the academic culture and am looking for new ways to get others excited about coding and to contribute to impactful meaningful projects throughout the tech space.

#### **EDUCATION**

# MS Technology, Media, and Society, CU Boulder

Fall 2018 - Present

• ATLAS Institute MS-CTD (Creative Technologies and Design program)

BS Math and Computer Science, Colorado School of Mines

Dec 2014

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Adjunct Professor,** Colorado School of Mines, Golden,CO

Spring 2018, Spring 2019

 Working with a team of instructors, each with their own section, teaching college level advanced programming concepts to students of all majors at Colorado School of Mines

#### **Internship,** Radial Development Group, Loveland, Co

Nov 2018 - Present

- Using networking and design skills to give the small software development agency at Radial a "heartbeat" on social media by researching technology and code online, reaching out and mentoring other users, and promoting Radial and other development agencies in Colorado
- Also cleaned up markdown files and did code/hack time as needed

# **Full Stack** .Net Developer, Clean Energy Collective, Louisville,CO

Mar 2016 - Apr 2017

- Engaged as the sole mid-level developer within a multi-discipline product development team of software developers, quality assurance, business, analysts, and project managers
- Mentored other developers in creating the Android mobile versions of the internal/external applications
- Created reporting feature for external application allowing utilities to gather all the data they can from solar powers
- Performed defect analysis and code rework using debugging tools in Visual Studio and Chrome
- Performed analysis of new feature proposals and recommendations to Business team
- Received corporate "Hot-Shot" award for rapid defect troubleshooting

# **Full Stack Software Developer,** Tyler Technologies, Lakewood,CO

Jan 2015 - Mar 2016

- Junior Developer within a multi-discipline development team of software developers, quality assurance, business, analysts, and project managers
- Performed defect analysis, code rework and new features code for Parcel Tax Management software used by for county offices nationwide
- Received 2<sup>nd</sup> place Creative Computing Award in the corporate Tax Division for the creation of GUI windows for client customers to visualize a full breakdown of their parcel taxes

#### Full Stack Web Developer, LDS Executive Coaching, Superior, CO

Jan - Mar 2014

- Created a full function corporate client website utilizing HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP, resulting in old and new clientele being able to reach him
- Integrated client database streams and website utilizing WampServer utility
- Actively pursued personal knowledge of Secure Forms, PHP prepared statements

## **SKILLS/STRENGTHS**

**Software:** .Net, C#, Java, C/C++, SQL, Fortran, HTML, CSS, Jekyll, PHP, Rails, SCSS

Hardware: Arduino, RaspberryPi, Soldering, Basic Circuits

Design : Adobe Suite, Rapid Prototyping, 3D Printing, Laser-cutting, UI/UX Design, Game Design

**Other**: Fluent in Greek, Proficient in French